Syed Ajmathulla

Address:-Do no:10-283, Currency Nagar-3, Vijayawada, Yanamalakuduru, Donka Road, AP 520007, 8328044343 sdajmathulla@gmail.com

FRONT END DEVELOPER

A Front End Developer is responsible for designing and implementing UI components for JavaScript-based web applications and mobile applications with the use of open-source library infrastructure. These developers are a part of the entire process starting from conception to the major testing process and follow popular Angular and Vue Js and Nuxt Js workflows.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and efficient developer having 1+ years experience with a vast array of knowledge in many different front end languages, responsive frameworks, databases, and best code practices. My objective is simply to be the best Angular developer that I can be and to contribute to the technology industry all that I know and can do. I am

dedicated to perfecting my craft by learning from more seasoned developers, remaining humble, and continuously making strides to learn all that I can about development, and I believe that my understanding of problem solving are also skills that have and will continue to contribute to my overall success as a developer. Seeking to further improve my skills as the future full stack developer at Atmospheric Solutions.

SKILLS

- Fluent knowledge of latest HTML5/CSS3,Bootstrap5,SCSS standards and best pract
- Working knowledge of JavaScript and Angular
- Solid Understanding of HTTP protocol and how server-side code is processed on the client
- Working knowledge of front end optimization and performance techniques
- Obsession with lean, clean and organized front-end code
- Experience building Responsive websites for web, tablet and mobile devices
- Eye for details is crucial
- Able to handle multiple projects and competing deadlines
- Good understanding of overall web design including basic usability, accessibility, industry standards, architecture, and navigation
- Detail oriented experience as a Web Developer creating Angular based solutions
- Ability to work both independently and in collaborative teams to communicate design and build ideas effectively
- Experience using asynchronous services (JSON)

WORK HISTORY

IT SECTOR RELEVANT EXPIRIENCE

OROTRON HYDERABAD TS : 01-07-2021 TO 27-12-2021

KJ SYSTEMS IND PVT LTD. VIJAYAWADA AP : 29-12-2021 TO PRESENT

Front End Developer May 2021 - Current Responsibilities:

- ●Analyzed business requirement to translate functional requirements into technical requirements using MVC based Angular, migrate JavaScript to Angular, replaced JavaScript objects with Angular modules, views, Components, Services, and Modals.
- Designed the front end using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap and Angular, changed resolution on different devices by Media Queries.
- ■Extensively used HTML5 features like local storage, new input attributes and ES6 features.
- Worked with Angular directives, components, filters and services to customize controllers.
- ■Built Angular Services to fetch data from web APIs, used Angular Resolve to restrict access to views with authorized information.
- Built Angular Controllers to control the data flow and handle user-raised events. Built Angular factories and services to facilitate communication across independent controllers.
- •Used ISON to process asynchronous http requests between customers and web application.
- •Worked on Routing in Angular, ensured secure http requests.
- Build dynamic, visually-attractive, end-to-end, and innovative software product/apps including front-end and back-end
- ●Able to design the user experience, user interaction, responsive design, and complete architecture
- ●Able to work with databases, servers, APIs, version control systems, and third-party apps
- Provide insights on continuous improvement and add/remove functionality as per needs
- Design strategy for continuous enhancement, performance optimization, stability, and scalability
- Stay updated with new tools, frameworks, approaches, and architectures in the development world
- Transform business needs into a finished product from conception to implementation.
- ●Ensure cross-platform compatibility and fixing issues during test and production phases

- ■Handle a team of developers and communicate well with them for product roadmap/performance enhancement
- ●Lead a team of developers, designers, and network managers and ensure digital outcomes are in line with business objectives
- A result-oriented professional with good communication, leadership, team management, analytical and co-ordination skills.

SIMPLE CONTACTS CRUD APP:

SITE URL : https://profile-scope.netl ify.app/login

<u>Using Angular 14 Desktop View and Mobile View</u>: Lifecycle Hooks, Controllers, Moduels, Services, Modals, Decorators, Angular Routing, Dependency Injection, HttpClientModules, FormModules, ReactiveFormModule, Pipes, Pure Pipes, and Impure Pipes Filters, and Observables, Router and ActivatedRouter, and Using queryParams, ParamMap, subscribe(), Method, get(), post(), put(), delete() Methods, and ErrorHandling, Authorisation and Authentic and loading spinner and Bootstrap5, @Input, @Output EventEmitter, @ViewChild, @ViewChildren, Using the Interfaces and Rxjs Observables, Angular Material, Feature Modules, LazyLoaded Modules. RouteGuards.

Download the source Code:

https://github.com/Ajju1197/Rolex_Crud_App

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript

Web Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, Angular ,ReactJS(basics), Vue JS, Nuxt JS, JSON,

HTML4/5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Entity Framework

Databases: Working Knowledge, SQL, MySQL.

Testing: BrowserDeveloper Tools.

IDE/Tools: Visual Studio 2015/2013, Atom, Visual Studio Code, Postman.

Version Control: Git.

Cloud Platform: Azure, Github

SOFT SKILLS

- Good communication and management skills
- Ability to adapt to new technology, concept, approaches, and environment faster
- Problem-solving and analytical skills
- Knowledge of non-functional aspects of the app/product such as security, automation, testing, performance, optimization
- Leadership and resource management skills

[&]quot;A respect for and admiration of the culture, process, and craft of Full Stack Web Developer, as well as an understanding of the client experience, appreciating what it takes to form long-term client relationships."

EDUCATION

NF ZP BOYS HIGH SCHOOL Board of Secondary Education (2012 - 2013) GPA: 7.3/10

SRI CHAITANYA JUNIOR COLLEGE Board of Intermediate Education (2013 – 2015) with an aggregate of 74%

PB SIDDHARTHA COLLEGE OF ARTS AND SCIENCE Bachelor of Science, (2015 - 2020) with an aggregate of 56.5%

PERSONAL PROFILES

Father's Name : Syed Karimulla Mother's Name : Syed Nasima

Address : Vijayawada Nationality : Indian Gender : Male

Marital status: Married

Languages Known: Telugu, English, and Hindi

DECLARATION

I am confident that I shall strive and succeed in the position applied to the Satisfaction of my superiors and justice the assignments entrusted on me.

Sincerely,

Syed Ajmathulla.

Email:- sdajmathulla@gmail.com,

Phone No:- 8328044343